MAN ON TV: Young people
from all over the globe
are joining up to fight for the future.
-I'm doing my part.
-I'm doing my part too.
(ALL LAUGHING)
They're doing their part, are you?
Join the Mobile Infantry
and save the world.
Service guarantees citizenship.
The Bug sent another meteor our way,
but this time we're ready.
Planetary defenses
are better than ever.
Klendathu, source
of the bug meteor attacks,
orbits a twin star system
whose brutal gravitational forces
produce an unlimited supply
of bug meteorites
in the form of this asteroid belt.
To ensure the safety
of our solar system
Klendathu must be eliminated.
We break net now
and take you live to Klendathu
where the invasion has begun.
MAN: EXQ uplink on two, one.
You're on.
We've just landed here on what
camp troopers are calling Big K,
with the 6th Mobile Infantry Division!
It's an ugly planet, a bug planet!
(ROARING)
A planet hostile to life as we know it!
(MAN SHOUTING)
Help me!
-Come on! Go, go, go!
-Keep moving!
Get out of here now!
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
(MAN SCREAMING)
Kit, no!
(SCREAMING)
Oh, God!
(GROANING)
Rico. Rico. Rico!
Pay attention.
Sorry, Mr. Rasczak.
Let's sum up.
This year we explored
the failure of democracy.
Bad boy.
RASCZAK: How the social scientists
brought our world to the brink of chaos.
We talked about the veterans,
how they took control
and imposed the stability
that has lasted for generations since.
You know these facts
but have I taught you anything
of value this year?
You,
why are only citizens allowed to vote?
It's a reward,
what the Federation gives you
for doing Federal Service.
No. No.
Something given has no value.
Look, when you vote,
you are exercising political authority.
You're using force.
And force, my friends, is violence,
the supreme authority
from which all other authority is derived.
My mother always said
violence never solves anything.
Really?
I wonder what the city fathers
of Hiroshima would say about that.
You.
They probably wouldn't say anything.
Hiroshima was destroyed.
Correct.
Naked force has resolved more issues
throughout history
than any other factor.
The contrary opinion,
(BEEPING)
that violence never solves anything,
is wishful thinking at its worst.
People who forget that always pay.
Rico, what's the moral difference,
if any,
between a civilian and a citizen?
A citizen accepts
personal responsibility for the safety
of the body politic,
defending it with his life.
-A civilian does not.
-The exact words of the text.
But do you understand it?
Do you believe it?
-I don't know.
-Of course you don't.
I doubt anyone here
would recognize civic virtue
if it reached up and bit you in the ass.
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
Not here.
Come on,
let's see if they posted the math final.
-Rico, we gonna take Tesla?
-We're gonna kill 'em.
WOMAN: Remember, all graduating
seniors must ﬁll out a 710 form.
First thing Fleet Academy
looks at is your math scores.
Wish me luck.
Good job.
Your turn. Hold on.
I want to talk to Marco.
His sister's at Fleet.
-Marco.
-Hi, Carmen.
CARMEN: What do you hear
about Roxy?
-MARCO: She made pilot.
-CARMEN: She did?
35%, very nice.
Look at that.
35%, ladies and gentlemen.
Big numbers.
-Carl.
-Sorry.
So, you haven't done it yet, have you?
Don't lie.
I'm not in any hurry.
(GIGGLING)
-Others are waiting.
-DIZZY: And?
-Did you read her mind?
-Don't have to.
It's pretty clear what she wants.
Yeah, but I want Carmen.
-You got it bad.
-CARMEN: Bye, Marco.
Hey, don't forget about this afternoon.
He's always late when he walks
you home to fish for a kiss.
Get out of here.
-Marco's sister made pilot.
-So will you.
I mean, imagine flying
a half a million tons of starship.
You gotta have nerves of steel.
Yeah, you do.
Let's see how yours hold up.
WOMAN: You may begin.
(GROANS)
Come on, it's just a bug.
You better put your goggles on.
"Just a bug."
We humans like to think
we are nature's finest achievement.
I'm afraid it just isn't true.
This Arkellian sand beetle
is superior in many ways.
It reproduces in vast numbers,
has no ego,
has no fear, doesn't know about death,
and so is the perfect selfless member
of society.
But humans have created art,
mathematics, and interstellar travel.
True. But before you let that go
to your head
take the example of the Arachnids,
a highly evolved insect society.
By human standards,
they are relatively stupid
but their evolution stretches
over millions of years.
-And now...
-Here, take this.
...they can colonize planets
by hurling their spore into space.
RICO: Okay, I think we got it.
The heart.
And here's the stomach.
DIZZY: Nerves of steel, huh?
(DIZZY LAUGHING)
Don't think about it. Just go on instinct.
Try to visualize it.
I see the ace of spades.
You know, statistically speaking,
you should have accidentally
guessed right by now. Try another.
So my psychic abilities are zero
and I'm unlucky.
No, luck's not a factor.
No one really knows why some people
are sensitive and some aren't.
Who knows? Maybe it's a new
stage of human evolution.
That's why they do these
kind of Federal studies.
What... Cyrano! Oh, shit. Time out.
You just want some attention.
You don't play with him any more.
Cyrano.
Go bug Mom, Cyrano.
(CHITTERING)
How do you make him do that?
Oh, I gave him the impression
there's a grub crawling up
my mom's leg.
He's on a mission to go eat it.
(MOTHER SCREAMS)
MOM: Get out! Get off my leg!
Carl!
I sure hope you don't do anything
like that to me.
Don't be afraid. Can't do human. Yet.
(CHEERING)
(GRUNTING)
Yeah!
All right!
-Are you all right?
-Much better. Now.
-PLAYER: Yeah!
-Way to go, team.
Hey! Your helmet.
So, what are you doing after the game?
Well, everyone's going to the dance,
aren't you?
I don't know.
It's my last night as a civilian.
-MAN: Come on, number 12! Let's go!
-Ship out for Tereshkova tomorrow.
You're going to the Fleet Academy?
That's where I want to go!
ANNOUNCER: Come on, number 12!
Let's play ball!
Don't get any ideas about my girlfriend!
All is fair in love and war.
-CHEERLEADERS: Giants! Giants!
-Johnny! Yeah!
PLAYER: Hut! Hut!
(WHOOPING)
Hey, yeah!
ANNOUNCER: Just over
42 seconds remaining.
-Yeah!
-DIZZY: All right, let's go.
Irvin, Latham, cover the rush.
Perry, fake left. Bertolli, you go long.
Rico, flip six, three hole. Got it?
Hey, Rico?
-Hey!
-What?
You're drifting!
Flip six, three hole, on one! Got it?
Just throw me the ball, Diz.
Ready? Break!
(TEAM GRUNTS)
Down. Set. Tight left.
-PLAYER: Screen!
-Hut!
(GRUNTING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Yeah! Go, go, go!
All right!
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
Yeah!
He's in there. It's over.
Who said you could grow up
so fast, huh?
Mom, don't get mushy.
This came for you today.
I presume at your request.
A lot of my friends
are doing Federal Service.
Well, you're not thinking of applying?
Have you lost your mind?
I'd rather take ten lashes
in Public Square
than see you ruin your life.
It's a term of service.
It's not a career.
I just want to get out on my own
see the galaxy for a couple of years.
Johnny, people get killed in
the Federal Service.
Who gave you this idea?
It's that teacher, isn't it?
What's his name?
You know the one I'm talking about.
-Mr. Rasczak.
-Rasczak?
(SCOFFS)
Silly name.
There should be a law against
using a school as a recruiting station.
No, Rasczak doesn't do that at all.
He sort of discourages you.
Well, that's good.
'Cause you're going to Harvard,
and that's the end of it.
It's my decision, not yours.
-Oh, is that how it is, huh?
-Wait, you two.
Dad and I have a surprise for you
that will settle this.
Can you guess what it is?
No.
You want to see the galaxy?
How about a trip to the Outer Rings?
Zegema Beach. Huh?
I've always wanted to go there.
Good, good. Then it's all settled.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
CARMEN: Sure. Don't go away.
RICO: I just need to see Mr. Rasczak.
Hey, Rico, do you want to dance?
Actually, Diz, I promised Carmen...
Come on.
Too bad for her if she's not around.
You know, it's sad,
after tonight, most of us
probably won't see each other again.
So, you still gonna play for Rio?
Yeah, looks like.
Unless Tokyo lets me start.
Well, anyone who gets you is lucky.
Johnny, how come
we never got together?
Can't we just be friends, Diz?
Sure.
-MAN: Thank you.
-Good night.
Look, Diz, I want to talk to Mr. Rasczak.
Well, you better hurry up
if you want to catch him.
You're the best.
-Mr. Rasczak!
-What is it, Rico?
I want to thank you.
Your class was the best one
I had this year.
Well, it's really not my job to please.
I just hope you learned something.
Well, I want to join up.
I think I got what it takes to be a citizen.
Good for you. Go find out.
Well, my parents are against it.
And I know it's my choice.
I was wondering...
What would you do if you were me?
Figuring things out for yourself
is the only freedom anyone really has.
Use that freedom.
Make up your own mind, Rico.
CARMEN: Don't exaggerate.
I'm serious.
I think you have really beautiful eyes.
Johnny.
This is Zander.
Yeah, we know each other
from the game.
No hard feelings?
No, none at all. We won.
Come on, Carmen. It's the last dance.
Well, maybe I'll see you
at the Academy.
Yeah. Who knows?
Good luck.
Zander's going for pilot too.
You two have so much in common.
Johnny Rico, are you jealous?
Well, maybe.
You don't have to be jealous.
Hey, hey, break it up, you two.
There's a place for that sort of thing.
I've been thinking,
and I'm gonna do it, Carmen.
I'm gonna go for Federal Service.
That's great.
Carl and l are signing up tomorrow.
Come with us.
I will.
My father's not home tonight.
-...my own free will
after having been
duly advised and warned
of the meaning and consequences
of this oath
enroll in the Federal Service
for not less than two years
and as much longer
as may be required
by the needs of the Federation.
Fresh meat for the grinder, eh?
So, how'd you kids do?
I'm gonna be a pilot.
(CHUCKLING) Good for you!
We need all the pilots we can get.
-Hey, did you get starside R and D?
-No.
-I don't believe it.
-I got Games and Theory.
Games and Theory?
-That's military intelligence.
-Yeah.
Way to go, Carl.
Next time we meet,
I'll probably have to salute you.
How about you, son?
-Infantry, sir.
-Good for you.
Mobile Infantry made me
the man I am today.
MAN ON PA: All recruits must report
to the Federal Transportation Hub
in 24 hours.
Welcome to the adventure
of Federal Service.
Let's make a vow.
No matter what,
we'll always be friends.
(CHUCKLING)
I'll go for that.
Well, chances are
we'll never see each other again.
We'll be millions of light-years
away from each other.
But, yeah, sure. Why not?
You'll resign, and that's all there is to it.
It may look bad,
but if that's the worst you suffer,
then that's fine.
-I won't quit!
-I'm telling you, you will.
You're not going back.
You're going on vacation!
I am not going on vacation!
I want to be a citizen.
It's my decision. I made it.
You walk out that door,
you are cutoff, young man.
You understand me?
All right, that's it! You are cutoff!
Johnny, why won't you
change your mind?
Does citizenship
mean that much to you?
Yeah, sure.
I hope so.
I hope you don't ruin your life
over some silly little girl
who wants you to look handsome
in a uniform.
-Don't talk about Carmen that way!
-Johnny.
WOMAN ON PA:
Your attention, please.
Outbound group 1380,
all hub 29 connections…
-MAN: Do you have everything?
-Moscow now boarding.
Great.
CARMEN: Johnny.
-RICO: You're late.
-My dad had to help me pack.
Suddenly he's afraid he's never
gonna see me again or something.
It was sweet, but it took forever.
Anyway, I guess I'm ready to go.
Yeah, me too.
I'm wearing everything I own.
I'm sorry your parents were mad.
Who cares? The Federation
will give me everything I need
for the next two years, right?
You talked to Carl?
Yeah, he left this morning.
Couldn't say where.
Oh, it's exciting, going away
but I'm scared. Aren't you?
I'm gonna miss you.
I'm gonna miss you too.
I love you.
WOMAN ON PA: Outbound group 94B
to Tereshkova…
CARMEN: That's me.
Just say it once. Try it on for size.
I love you.
Don't forget to write.
I won't.
SOLDIER: Fully automatic Morita.
Who wants to hold it?
-Me! Me! Me!
MAN ON TV: Citizen rule.
People making a better tomorrow.
(CHILDREN CLAMORING)
(CHUCKLING)
A murderer was captured
this morning and tried today.
Guilty.
Sentence, death.
Execution tonight at 6:00.
All net. All channels.
If you think you're psychic,
maybe you are.
MAN ON TV: Federal studies
are being conducted
in your community.
Would you like to know more?
Every school kid knows
that Arachnids are dangerous.
(ROARING)
However, Mormon extremists
disregarded Federal warnings
and established Fort Joe Smith
deep inside
the Arachnid Quarantine Zone.
Too late, they realized
that Dantana had already
been chosen by other colonists,
Arachnids.
Would you like to know more?
-SOLDIER: One, two, three, four!
-Ten-hut!
Most of you will not live
to be in the Mobile Infantry.
The trouble is, you are not good enough
the way you are.
Hands at your side!
Chin up.
I am your senior drill instructor,
Career Sergeant Zim!
Suck in that gut! Feet together!
(GROANING)
To think this had to happen to me.
What a bunch of apes.
No, strike that!
You don't rate that good.
Never in my life have I seen...
(CHUCKLING)
Do you think I'm funny?
Do I make you laugh?
-Do you think I'm a comedian, son?
-I'm sorry.
The first words and the last words out
of your stinking holes will be "Sir"!
-Do you get me?
-Sir, yes, sir!
You see that armory? Run around it.
(MOANS)
Run, I said! Run, run, run!
-Bronski, keep pace!
-BRONSKI: Move! Move!
Now, anytime you think
I'm being too tough,
anytime you think I'm being unfair,
anytime you miss your mommy, quit!
You sign form 1240 A,
you grab your gear
you take a stroll down Washout Lane!
Do you get me?
-CADETS: Sir, yes, sir!
-Pathetic!
I wonder if there's a handful of guts
in the whole bunch of you.
Now, who here thinks they got
what it takes to knock me down?
Sir! I guess maybe I do, sir!
(SHOUTING)
(BONE SNAPPING)
CADET: (GROANING)
God! God!
-You all right, son?
-Sir, yes, sir!
It's my arm. I think it's broken, sir.
-Medic!
-CADET: God! God!
ZIM: Pain is in your mind!
-Who's next?
-DIZZY: Sir!
Recruit Flores reporting for duty, sir!
You specifically requested transfer
from Fort Cronkite to this training unit?
Sir, I heard it was the best, sir!
It is the best.
But what makes you think
you're good enough?
Now that's the kind of gal
who makes squad leader.
That's my job you're talking about.
Come on.
(GRUNTING)
(GASPING)
You know, I'd like to kill
that Sergeant Zim.
-Improper attitude!
-MAN: Watch it.
They'll kick you out for talking like that.
Bye-bye.
There you go down Washout Lane.
Yes, you either got what it takes,
or you don't.
-Hey, there is a line.
-Wait your turn, Ace.
Hey, at ease, little soldier.
It's all the same muck.
Get in line like everyone else.
You got some guts for a rich kid.
I guess you and me could be buddies.
What do you say?
-I'm honored.
-Hey! Of course you are.
Everybody should have
a friend like me.
Come on, Ace, back of the line.
Back of the line! Back! Back! Back!
-What a jerk, man.
-Tough guy.
Hey, Rico, want to sit together?
No thanks, Diz.
What's your malfunction, Rico?
You are.
I joined up to get out on my own,
and you had to tag along.
You think I joined the Mobile Infantry
because of you?
You saying you didn't?
Hi.
RICO: Forget about it, Ace.
You don't stand a chance.
What makes you even think
you're gonna make squad leader, Rico?
Something I got, you don't.
You rich kids are all the same.
It isn't about that.
It's about who's the best.
Hey!
(GRUNTING)
ZIM: Third squad!
(GRUNTS)
Sir, I don't understand.
Who needs a knife
in a nuke fight, anyway?
All you gotta do is push a button, sir.
Cease fire.
Put your hand on that wall, trooper.
Put your hand on that wall!
(GROANING)
The enemy cannot push a button
if you disable his hand.
Medic!
Well, we all have one thing in common.
We were all stupid enough
to sign up for Mobile Infantry.
Breckinridge, what's your excuse?
Oh, my family's all farmers.
I hate farming. I mean, Mobile Infantry,
it's like pure picnic by comparison.
All right, so they grow 'em big
and dumb on the farm planet, huh?
-And pretty!
-WOMAN: I like big!
Djana'D, what about you?
Oh, I'm going in for politics
and, you know,
you gotta be a citizen for that.
-So here I am.
-Ah, you want some responsibility.
Yeah.
Shujimi, come on, let's keep it going.
I got into Harvard,
but my father says forget it.
It's gonna cost an arm and a leg.
So, if I serve, Federation pays my way.
I want to have babies.
You know, it's a lot easier
to get a license if you've served, so...
I'm going career.
Officer's training. All the way.
Future Sky Marshal.
All right, Rico, your turn.
Who asked you to be so nosy?
What? I'm the bad guy?
I'm gonna be a writer.
Writer's got a right to be nosy.
Hey, Flores, you know
Rico from Buenos Aires.
What's his story?
He's here because of a girl.
(ALL CHEERING)
Oh, Rico! Lover boy!
-KITTEN: He's getting me excited.
-KATRINA: He's gonna blow.
(ALL LAUGHING AND WHOOPING)
Is it you?
RICO: This is where we live.
It's not much, but it's home.
(VIOLIN PLAYING)
Right there, that's my bunk,
where I dream about you every night.
Boot's pretty tough.
Sometimes I think I won't make it.
Then I think about what you're doing,
and I try harder.
(HOLLERING)
(FARTING NOISE)
-RICO: Hey, guys! Do you mind?
-Try harder, baby, try harder!
Who knows? They might even
make me squad leader.
(BUGLE SOUNDING)
Uh-oh. I'd better pack it in.
(SCREAMING)
-I love you so much.
-Write me!
-RICO: I'm gonna kill you guys!
-Bye! Write me.
-KATRINA: Bye!
Orbit in five, Ibanez.
First one there gets to fly.
(BOTH GIGGLING)
-Locking it down.
-MAN: Wait! Wait!
Oh, no. Not Ibanez again. She's crazy!
Ready, go!
Yeah!
WOMAN: Deploying wings.
How come you're in
such a good mood, huh?
'Cause today I get to fly that.
Pilot Trainee Ibanez
reporting for duty, ma'am.
Take the number two chair, Ibanez.
Yes, ma'am.
-Identify.
-COMPUTER: Ibanez, T 325 A, clear.
(LAUGHING)
What are you doing here?
I'm the guy who's gonna teach you
to fly this crate.
Assistant Instructor.
Should I call you "sir"?
-Only when I give you an order.
-Prepare for departure.
It's amazing,
us running into each other like this.
-Maybe it's fate.
-Maybe not.
Heard about this crazy girl
coming through the Academy.
Solid math, a little wild on the stick,
but a natural.
And when it turned out to be you,
I just made sure
that we would run into each other.
WOMAN ON PA: Rodger Young
cleared for undocking and departure.
All right, Ibanez, take her out.
Yes, ma'am.
WOMAN ON PA: All systems go.
(ENGINE STARTS)
In simulation,
my supervisors could never keep up.
Well, this isn't simulation any more,
so take her out easy, cadet.
Yes, sir.
(BEEPING)
COMPUTER: Five meters from object.
Three meters from object.
Clear.
-Don't exceed port speed.
-Or what?
Or they revoke your flight status,
and mine.
Your career is in my hands.
Steady as she goes, Number Two.
-Prepare for warp.
-Yes, ma'am.
Number One, design for Jupiter orbit.
MAN ON PA: All crew, all sections,
stand by to cut in C drive.
-Star drive in five, four...
-MAN ON PA: Five, four,
-three, two, one.
-ZANDER: ...ready, steady, go!
(WHOOSHING)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
(YELLING)
We're going in! Move!
(GRUNTING)
Man, they're defended. No way in.
(LAUGHING)
-Flip six, three hole.
-What?
You run a flip six, three hole play,
and you can score.
-Cover me.
-You got it.
Now!
-Thanks, buddy.
-Bastard!
Yeah!
Kid's got some moves.
Give him a squad. See what he can do.
ACE: Kitty, Kitty.
Someone's got to teach you guys
how to play some pool here.
Look at him.
Have you ever seen anybody
so pleased with himself?
Well, Zim must have had to choose
someone to be his brownnose.
All right, where were we?
Okay, watch and learn.
I couldn't have done it without you, Diz.
Fﬂends?
Friends.
-BRONSKI: Mail call! Levy!
-Yeah, that's me.
-Shujimi!
-Here.
-Rico.
-Breckinridge!
-Yeah, right here.
-Niler.
-Yeah, here I am. Ah, great, my dad.
BRONSKI: That's all, folks.
Hi, Johnny.
I'm sorry I haven't written you sooner,
but it's been really busy.
Oh, Rico, you don't deserve that!
They've really got us going here.
They must have made you
squad leader by now.
And if they haven't,
tell 'em to talk to me.
See? All it takes is
the love of a good woman.
-ACE: Yeah.
-That is a woman.
-Look at that.
-ACE: Look at those.
Isn't it beautiful? I love it out here.
(SIGHS)
That's also the problem
because, I think I'm gonna go career.
I want to command a ship of my own.
And you know,
I don't think that's gonna leave
a lot of room for you and me, Johnny.
(SIGHS)
I know that's not what you wanted
to hear.
But
I have to follow my heart. I'm sorry.
Write me, all right?
Write me so that I know
we'll always be friends.
BRECKINRIDGE: Let's get back
to the game.
DJANA'D: I feel so sorry for Johnny.
Funny how they always want
to be friends
after they rip your guts out, huh?
Yeah. Well, it's what I deserve.
What are you talking about?
I joined up for her.
I wouldn't even be here
if it wasn't for her.
What are you talking about?
You made squad leader on your own.
And, hey, you still got me
to kick around.
ZIM: Fun and games are over, children.
You will be firing live ammunition
in a simulated combat environment.
You will exercise extreme caution
on my assault course!
Do you get me?
-Sir, yes, sir!
Rico, take 'em out!
First fire team with me.
Next team in 10 seconds.
Maximum score has been 280.
I expect you to do better!
(BUZZER SOUNDS)
RICO: Go!
(ALL YELLING)
RICO: Shujimi, stay down!
(CRIES OUT)
Hey! God damn it, Breckinridge,
clear my line of fire!
It's my helmet! It's all screwed up!
You're gonna blow the score!
-Damn.
-Dumb shit.
Diz, stay put! What's the problem?
Damn thing keeps getting in my way!
How come whenever something goes
wrong, it's always you, Breckinridge?
-It must be 'cause I'm big and dumb!
-Yeah, right!
Medic!
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
ZIM: Rico, you are relieved
of squad command!
Rico, did you give the recruit
permission to remove his helmet?
Sir, yes, sir. Breckinridge
reported a helmet malfunction
and I asked him to show it to me, sir.
Are you rated to repair
the M-3 Tactical Helmet, Rico?
Sir, no, sir!
Then why did you order your man
to remove his helmet
during a live fire exercise?
Sir, I needed everyone
in my squad operational, sir!
I wanted to win, sir!
Sergeant, we've already lost
two recruits over this incident.
You think there's any possibility
of salvaging this man?
Yes, sir, I do.
All right.
We'll try administrative punishment.
Prisoner, halt!
Bite down on this, son.
It helps. I know.
For incompetence
of command,
for failure to abide by safety regulations
during a live fire exercise,
for negligence which contributed
to the death of a teammate,
recruit trainee John Rico
is sentenced to
administrative punishment.
Ten lashes.
You may carry out the sentence.
(GROANING)
One!
Two!
(GROANING)
Three!
Four!
(GROANING)
Five!
(GROANS)
Six!
Seven!
Eight!
Nine!
Ten!
MAN ON COMPUTER: All sections
secure. EBS is high normal.
Switching to slave on my mark. Mark.
Thanks. You read my mind.
Oh, third watch
always seems to last forever.
I don't know.
Depends on who
you're spending it with.
Something's wrong.
-There.
-No, I replotted the course.
-It's more efficient this way.
-Three weeks aboard a starship
and you think
that you can lick my navs?
Check it.
You know, I was talking
with Captain Deladier
and, she said...
(CHUCKLING) Don't change
the subject.
Am I right?
(SIGHS)
Yeah. Yeah. You're right.
So, what did the Captain say?
She thinks that we ought
to team up officially
and crew for her.
-You and me, huh?
-We're good together, Carmen.
We're way ahead of the curve
in every department.
I can anticipate you.
You know what I want.
No. What do you want?
(RUMBLING)
There's a gravity field out there.
-Run a scan. Sensors on.
-There.
-CARMEN: Gravity at 225 and rising.
-Report.
Captain, we're in the path
of an unidentified object
moving toward us at high speed.
Profile suggests an asteroid, ma'am.
-Impact, six seconds!
-Emergency evasion!
Three, two,
(ALARM BUZZING)
fire!
Close compartment 21.
Where'd it come from?
It came out of
the Arachnid Quarantine Zone, ma'am.
Number Four, contact Fleet.
Tell 'em there's a loose asteroid
headed their way.
Communications are down, ma'am.
They're gone.
-Damage assessment.
-Hull's compromised.
We're lucky to be alive, ma'am.
Luck didn't have anything to do with it.
We have a hell of a flight team.
(SIGHING)
It really stinks, you going.
Yeah, well, the Mobile Infantry
will just have to get along without me.
I don't get it, Rico. You took your licks.
If they didn't want you,
they would have kicked you out.
Hey...
I joined up for the wrong reasons.
I got a guy killed.
I figure that kind of proves
I don't have what it takes.
Rico, your call's going through.
Take it there.
-Hello? Oh, Johnny!
-Hi, Mom.
Bill, pick it up. It's Johnny!
-Johnny?
-Dad.
-Where's your uniform?
-Bill.
It's just good to hear from you.
How are you, son?
It's not really working out here
for me, Dad.
I was thinking...
I was hoping it would be all right
if I came home.
Well, of course.
You should come home immediately.
I'm sorry. I've been an idiot.
Don't talk like that. You just come
on home, talk things out.
We love you, son.
-My, what's that?
-Looks like rain.
-This time of year?
-Sure is dark.
WOMAN: Your transmission
has been terminated
due to atmospheric interference.
Please try your call again later.
Well, see you.
Hey, you take that stroll
down Washout Lane
you're only proving one thing, Johnny.
What's that, Diz?
That you don't have what it takes
to be a citizen.
(CADETS SINGING)
(CONFUSED SHOUTING)
What's going on?
Hey, Kitten, what's going on?
War! We're going to war!
MAN ON TV: The devastation
we are seeing is unparalleled.
Judging from early estimates,
millions dead, a city in ruins.
Is that Geneva?
Goddamn bugs whacked us, Johnny.
The meteor was shot out
of orbit by bug plasma
that derived from Klendathu,
the Arachnids' home planet.
Nothing lives in what was once called
"The Latin Paradise. "
Oh, Johnny, it's us.
Buenos Aires has been wiped off
the Earth.
That's home.
The Federal Council met moments ago
and voted unanimously
for mobilization
to destroy the Arachnid threat.
ZIM: I'm serious. I'll go anywhere.
Forget it, Zim. We need you here.
I want combat, sir.
The only way you're gonna see combat
is if you bust yourself to private!
-Get me?
-Yes, sir, I get you.
-Sir!
-What do you want, Rico?
I wish to reconsider my request
to drop out, sir.
You already signed your 1240 A, son.
-It wouldn't be legal.
-Major, I know it was wrong.
I didn't learn from one mistake,
and I made another, sir.
You made your decision, son.
Sir, my family, my whole family,
was in Buenos Aires, sir.
Is this your signature, Rico?
Sir, yes, that is, sir!
Doesn't look like it to me.
-Carry on, Private!
-Yes, sir!
MAN ON TV: Out of the ashes
of Buenos Aires comes first sorrow,
then anger.
The only good bug is a dead bug.
In Geneva,
the Federal Council convenes.
We must meet the threat
with our valor, our blood
indeed, with our very lives
to ensure that human civilization,
not insect,
dominates this galaxy, now and always!
MAN ON TV: Sky Marshal Dienes
announces plans
for an offensive against Klendathu,
source of the bug meteor
that destroyed Buenos Aires.
Every day, Federal scientists
are looking for new ways to kill bugs.
Your basic Arachnid warrior
isn't too smart
but you can blow off a limb,
and it's still 86 percent
combat effective.
Here's a tip, aim for the nerve stem,
and put it down for good.
Would you like to know more?
Everyone's doing their part. Are you?
The war effort needs your effort
at work, at home, in your community.
We now break net and take you live
to Fleet Battle Station, Ticonderoga,
deep inside
the Arachnid Quarantine Zone
where the men and women of
the Federal Armed Services
prepare to attack.
MAN: DXQ, uplink on two, one,
You're on.
No one here in the AQZ knows exactly
when the invasion
of Klendathu will occur.
But everyone's talking about it
and the talk says tomorrow.
Here's a bunch of MI kids
that look like
they could eat bugs for lunch.
-(CHUCKLING) Yum, yum, yum.
-So, trooper,
you're not too worried
about fighting the Arachnids?
Shoot a nuke down a bug hole,
you got a lot of dead bugs. Am I right?
I just hope it's not over
before we get some.
Some say the bugs were provoked
by the intrusion of humans
into their natural habitat,
that a "Live and let live policy"
is preferable to war with the bugs.
Let me tell you something.
I'm from Buenos Aires,
and I say kill them all!
-Yeah!
-Yeah, okay!
Big bad bugs, huh?
Hey, guys, we ought to get tattoos.
-Hey, let's all get out together.
-What do I want a tattoo for?
Oh, what? Your skin's too pretty?
Come on, everybody's doing it.
CARMEN: Hey, Johnny!
Johnny Rico.
Carmen?
At ease.
Guess I ought to lose the hat
when I'm off duty.
-Hi, Diz.
-Carmen.
My mother was right about you.
You look great in a uniform.
You look pretty good yourself.
So, what do you hear?
You know about anyone
who made it out of BA alive?
Most of the time I don't think about it.
Like it happened to someone else.
Then it hits me, and I can't stop crying.
Well, we're still alive.
Got to be happy about that.
You don't look very happy to see me.
Should I be?
Johnny, it's different now.
We're at war.
I think what I did was probably
the best thing for both of us.
Everything copacetic, Lieutenant?
Zander, you remember Johnny.
Zander and I are a flight team now.
Yeah, and we're best in the fleet.
I get it.
This is the part
that's best for both of us.
-Don't do me any more favors.
-Johnny, wait.
No, forget it, Lieutenant.
He's Mobile Infantry.
See, when you're trained to kill,
it just doesn't pay to be polite.
You got something to say
about the Mobile Infantry?
I think you heard me.
You want to make something of it,
Private?
Not with an officer. No, sir.
The MI doesn't mint stupid troopers.
Well, let's disregard rank.
-Zander, please.
-TROOPER: Let it go, Rico. Let it go.
Everybody hear that?
Rank is not an issue here.
-Don't do this.
-Come on. What's he gonna do?
(CROWD CHEERING)
(GRUNTING)
ZANDER: Come on, jarheads!
Let go of me! Come on!
I'm gonna kill you!
I'm gonna kill you! I'll kill you!
Guys! Guys! Quit it! Enough! Come on!
Come on!
Forget it, Rico! Mobile Infantry
and Fleet don't mix. Come on.
Come on, let's go.
Jarheads.
-ACE: Mobile Infantry rules!
-KITTEN: Yeah!
Oh, God, that hurts.
Hey, well, I got something that might
hurt just a little bit more, buddy.
Oh, yeah! We're gonna fight,
and we're gonna win!
-Yeah!
(ALL HOOTING)
CAPTAIN: This is the captain speaking.
All personnel, prepare for drop.
We are at D-minus three and counting.
We are going in with first wave.
Means more bugs for us to kill.
You smash the entire area.
You kill anything that has
more than two legs.
You get me?
-We get you, sir!
-Plasma, ma'am, from the planet.
-Bug batteries.
According to military intelligence,
it'll be random and light.
Drop status?
Drop is 35% complete, ma'am.
Steady as she goes, Number Two.
(MOANING NERVOUSLY)
Remember your training,
and you will make it back alive!
(RETCHING)
(PANTING)
(HOWLING)
This isn't random or light.
Someone made a mistake.
That's it. We're empty, ma'am.
Someone made
a big goddamn mistake!
Break for high orbit!
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
(SHOUTING)
Move it!
(PANTING)
-Rockets up!
-Rocket crew, move up!
-Nuke 'em! Levy! Rico!
-Heat 'em up!
-Set.
-ACE: Fire!
-Follow me!
-Let's go!
(SHOUTING)
First platoon, left flank!
Split up! First and second squads,
follow me.
Two, cover! One, with me!
MAN: Along side! Side to side!
(ROARING)
Fire!
(SCREECHING)
(SHOUTING)
Here they come!
-Ace, what are we doing?
-I don't know.
(ROARING)
-KiII them! Kill them all!
(GUNS FIRING)
(ROARING)
(SCREECHING)
Come on!
Come on! Come on! You want some?
Here's some! Yeah!
Here's some of this!
(SCREAMS)
Oh, my God!
Shujimi!
No! No!
(SCREAMING)
Help! Help! Get out!
God!
(YELLING)
(ALL ROARING)
Let's get out of here!
Fall back!
(SHOUTING)
(ROARING)
(SCREAMING)
WOMAN: Mayday!
MAN ON RADIO: All units,
fall back to retrieval.
RICO: What's going on?
-Repeat…
-You got com?
It's a general retreat! Back to the boats!
REPORTER: We've just landed here
on what camp troopers are calling Big K
with the 6th Mobile Infantry Division.
It's an ugly planet, a bug planet.
A planet hostile to life as we...
(ROARING)
(SHOUTING)
Help me!
(YELLING)
ACE: Squad right!
(REPORTER SHOUTING)
(BUG SHRIEKING)
Come on! Go! Go! Go!
Get out of here now!
Watch your flanks!
MAN: GXR, we're being overrun.
(BUG ROARING)
(ROARING)
Kitten, no!
KITTEN: God! Oh, God!
(KITTEN GROANING)
(SHRIEKING)
(CRIES OUT)
(YELLING)
(BUG SCREECHING)
(SHOUTING)
MAN ON TV: Crisis for humankind.
Fleet officials admit
they underestimated
the Arachnids' defensive capability.
Accepting responsibility for Klendathu
Sky Marshal Dienes resigns.
His successor,
Sky Marshal Tahat Meru
outlines her new strategy.
To fight the bug
we must understand the bug.
We can ill afford another Klendathu.
Would you like to know more?
Federal scientists struggle to explain
the intelligent military actions
of the Arachnids.
When a colony reaches a certain size,
300 generations or something,
it gets smarter.
Insects with intelligence?
Have you ever met one?
I can't believe
I am hearing this nonsense.
You just wait a moment!
This is the most ridiculous
conversation I have ever had.
Maybe, there is some kind of bug
that we haven't seen yet,
a leadership caste, a hive brain.
Brain? Bugs? Frankly, I find
the idea of a bug that thinks offensive!
CARMEN: Ticonderoga,
this is Rodger Young
requesting approach vector.
MAN ON RADIO:
Affirmative, Rodger Young.
One, zero, zero, niner, five, two.
Welcome back.
ZANDER: My God.
How could this happen?
We thought we were smarter
than the bugs.
MAN: Give me something, please!
It hurts!
MEDIC: Be right with you, sir.
(GROANING)
MAN: Help me, God!
It's strange.
There's almost no wounded at all.
Bugs don't take prisoners.
Oh, no.
TROOPER: Look!
-Carmen...
-TROOPER: See it? Right there.
ACE: There he is.
DIZZY: Come on,
we'll just wake him up.
Hey, Johnny! Hey!
ACE: Hey, Rico!
DIZZY: Hey, Johnny!
How you doing, fish boy?
DIZZY: Wake up!
Hey, look. You're dead!
Killed in action!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
-Three more days.
-Three days.
-You're out.
-Good as new. See you later.
Bye.
So what do you hear
about our new unit?
Roughnecks killed more bugs
than any other outfit on Big K.
Yeah, well, I hear their lieutenant's
a real nutbuster.
Who's top kick?
(GUN CLICKING)
You want the job, huh?
I wouldn't mind.
I would.
Just doing my part.
Orders.
Yours?
Where you been besides Big K?
Outer rings, Zegema Beach.
Zegema Beach?
I always wanted to go there.
Good luck. It's not there any more.
So, I hear your lieutenant's
a real nutbuster.
(GRUNTING)
No one talks about
the lieutenant that way.
-He saved my life.
-Mine too.
-Same for me.
-Me too.
Well, sounds like he's quite a guy.
Who do you think saved your ass?
Stand by. Attention on deck!
This is for you new people.
I only have one rule,
everyone fights, no one quits.
You don't do your job, I'II shoot you.
Do you get me?
We get you, sir!
-Welcome to the Roughnecks.
-Rasczak's Roughnecks!
(ALL GRUNT)
At ease. Listen up.
We got a new Sky Marshal
and a new battle plan.
We're gonna clean out
the systems outlying Klendathu
one planet at a time.
Tomorrow we hit Tango Urilla.
After Fleet glasses the planet,
MI mops up.
Carry on.
(ROARING)
(SCREECHING)
All right. Spread out!
Fire teams!
You locate a bug hole, nuke it.
Watkins, shake out Flores and Rico.
Copy that. Move out!
First platoon, we're going for that ridge.
Levy, you're with me.
ACE: No, I'm in A Squad.
I'm going with Rico.
BIRDIE: Shut up and follow me!
(SCREECHING)
(BUG SHRIEKING)
(BUG WHIMPERING)
(SHRIEKING WEAKLY)
Hey, you like that?
Fungus-sucking sack of maggot puke!
It's dead, Watkins! It's dead!
Ain't much to look at
after you scrape them off your boot.
Bug hole. There.
(GUN FIRING)
(BUGS ROARING)
(SCREECHING)
Nuke 'em, Rico!
(WEAPON BEEPING)
Fire in the hole!
BIRDIE: Watkins, we're under
heavy attack. Position M-4.
-Get over here!
-Move!
-You got a bug problem, ma'am?
-Stow it, trooper!
Tanker!
(ROARING)
-Oh, shit!
-Come on! Move!
(ROARING)
Get down!
(SCREAMING)
RASCZAK: Come on!
(GRUNTING)
(BUG SHRIEKING)
(GRENADE BEEPING)
(CADETS CHEERING AND HOWLING)
TROOPER: Stay down, sucker!
Gillespie.
-Call for retrieval.
-GILLESPIE: Medic!
Nice moves.
Where'd you learn
how to do that, soldier?
Back in school, sir.
Don't you remember?
I was captain of the team.
-Rico.
-Sir.
I need a corporal.
You're it until you're dead
or till I find somebody better.
Thank you, sir.
-All right, saddle up! Show's over.
-Way to go, Corporal.
-I need a squad leader.
-Oh, no. I've been there and blew it.
I'm just here to fight.
What about it, Diz?
Looks like I'm your girl, sir.
(ALL GRUNT)
Listen up!
I expect the best, and I give the best!
Here's the beer!
(ALL CHEERING)
Here's the entertainment!
(ALL HOOTING)
Have fun! That's an order!
This one's for me!
Thank you, Lieutenant!
WATKINS: Rico!
You kill bugs good.
Thanks.
You knew the Lieutenant before the war.
What was he like?
He was a teacher.
Kind of like, he knew it all.
He always had this little smile.
Yeah, well, he don't smile much
any more.
Yeah, well, I guess your bottle fills up
real quick when your kids get smeared.
-Come on, Corporal.
-No, I don't do that any more.
I remember when you used to dance.
Come on.
Do I have to pull rank?
Excuse me, sir.
Rico. You once asked me for advice.
-Want some now?
-Yes, sir.
Lieutenant, HQ is on the com.
Never pass up a good thing.
Watkins, beer?
(CHUCKLES)
(SLOW MUSIC BEING PLAYED)
(CHUCKLING) Ace.
So, Rico, what are you doing
after the dance?
(DIZZY GIGGLING)
What's so funny?
Just the way things work out.
We finally got together, Diz.
I love you, Johnny.
RASCZAK: Rico!
(UNZIPPING)
We're moving out.
There's been a distress call
from General Owen on Planet P.
So get your shit wired
and report in 10 minutes.
Yes, sir.
Who's that with you?
Flores, sir.
Make it 20 minutes.
RICO: Yes, sir.
(GIGGLING)
20 minutes?
We can do it.
Whiskey Outpost, do you copy?
This is Roughneck 2-0 on tac three.
Come in, please.
Whiskey Outpost, Whiskey Outpost,
this is Roughneck 2-0 on tac three.
-Any contact with General Owen?
-No, sir.
Not even the transponder signal.
It's these canyons.
Go to higher ground, Sergeant.
Whiskey Outpost, Whiskey Outpost
this is Roughneck 2-0 on...
(BUG SCREECHING)
(SOLDIER SCREAMS)
TROOPER: Look out!
(SCREECHING AND ROARING)
(SCREAMING)
Sugar, your weapon.
Help me!
(SCREAMING)
(GUN FIRES)
I'd expect anyone in this unit
to do the same for me.
-Rico.
-Sir.
You're acting sergeant. Move 'em out.
You heard the lieutenant! Saddle up!
(DIZZY GROANS)
Gee, someone really humped the bunk.
-Watkins.
-Sir.
Secure this compound.
Police these bodies.
Yes, sir.
Give me three up on the tower, now!
OP there! OP there!
-TROOPER: Away!
-Number Two, police up these bodies!
Stinks in there.
-Rico!
-Yes, sir.
We need retrieval. This place crawls.
Get somebody in the communications
tent and get me an uplink.
Yes, sir. Diz, check it out.
RASCZAK: Command group with me.
(TROOPER SHOUTING ORDERS)
ACE: Shit.
Lieutenant!
Dirty bugs came in right
while they were having chow.
(GROANS IN DISGUST)
RASCZAK: Yeah, this is where
they got in.
DIZZY: Lieutenant.
I think you're gonna want to see this.
RASCZAK: What do you got, Flores?
God, I hate this place.
What does that look like to you, Rico?
Looks like a bug was in his brain, sir.
(GULPING)
They sucked his brains out.
(CRASHING)
Open that.
(MAN SHOUTING)
Officer on the deck!
-Pick up the general.
-Gone? Is it safe?
-We've got to get out of here!
-General!
Sir!
Thank God for you, all of you.
You're all gonna be heroes.
Every last one of you.
-Close that hole.
-Yes, sir.
I had to evade capture.
The security of the Federation
was at stake.
ACE: Fire in the hole!
l have operational knowledge
of what we're up to out here.
-Flores, I need that uplink.
-Working on it, sir.
GENERAL: See?
They get in your mind.
Look, they did it to Farley.
They got in his mind.
They make you do things.
They made Farley call headquarters.
The distress call was a trap.
They're just like us.
They want to know what makes us tick.
They want to know us,
so they can kill us.
Roughnecks, this is lead.
Prepare for attack.
-I repeat, we're gonna be attacked.
-Where's the retrieval boat?
Mayday. Mayday. This is Roughneck
2-0 to Battlegroup. Do you read?
Oh, God! We're gonna die!
Don't you understand?
We're all gonna die!
(GRUNTS)
Control yourself, General.
I can't. I can't.
I wish you'd just shoot me.
Lieutenant! He's just a little
out of his mind, sir.
Bugs! Bugs!
-Die!
-All right.
Warm it all up! Everything you've got!
Come on, you apes!
You want to live forever?
TROOPER 1: Here!
TROOPER 2: I got bugs!
(SOLDIERS SHOUTING)
(ROARING AND SCREECHING)
Fire at will!
(GRUNTING)
(SHRIEKING)
(BUG MOANING)
Incoming!
(SCREECHING)
(GROANING)
(BUGS SCREECHING)
No! Hey!
TROOPER: Watch your fire!
Rico, where's my communication?
-Diz, status on the uplink!
-DIZZY: Give me a minute.
We don't have a minute!
DIZZY: Battlegroup,
this is Roughneck 2-0. We are...
MAN ON RADIO: This is Rodger Young.
Go ahead.
We are under attack, sir.
We need retrieval now!
We have Planet P as clear.
This place crawls, sir.
We need pickup now!
-What's your position?
-Come down on this transmission.
Inside the outpost? That's crazy!
Well, I hope you have a crazy pilot.
Out!
(BUGS SCREECHING)
RICO: Lieutenant!
Boat coming down, sir!
Fall back into the compound! Fall back!
(TROOPER SCREAMING)
(BUG ROARS)
(TROOPER SCREAMS)
Hold here! Hold what you've got!
Running low!
I'm out!
Here, make 'em count!
(SCREECHING)
(SHIP WHOOSHING)
Make cover fire! Fall back!
Move, move, move!
Fall back to the boat! Haul ass!
(RASCZAK SHOUTING)
(GRUNTING)
-Oh, my God!
-Oh!
(SHOUTING)
Rico! Rico!
-You know what to do!
-Yes, sir!
Do it, Rico!
(GULPING)
(HOOTING)
-Yeah!
-Dizzy!
(BUG GROWLING)
(DIZZY SCREAMING)
RICO: No!
Ace, help me! Hold her down!
(SCREAMING)
ACE: Move! Get her into the boat!
Come on, Diz! Don't die on me!
ACE: Get out! Let's go!
(COUGHING)
Let's go! Get aboard!
Tower, let's go!
Let's move it, tower!
Run!
(TROOPERS SCREAMING)
Lift off!
(SCREECHING)
(GASPING)
-Johnny, I'm dying.
-No.
You're gonna be all right, Diz.
It's all right
because I got to have you.
(GASPING)
Johnny, don't let me go!
(COUGHING)
MAN ON RADIO: This is traffic control.
Proceed on vector
five-niner-two-two-seven.
I think you should know
your friend Rico is back there.
Get on the com and tell Fleet
to glass that rock.
On whose authority, Corporal?
That would be mine, sir.
I assumed command of the mission.
Rodger Young, we have an
official request by the Mobile Infantry
to commence bombardment of Planet P.
I thought you were dead.
I'm not, but a lot of my troopers are.
Negative on your request, DeRuyter.
The Sky Marshal has
other plans for Planet P.
Welcome back.
MI does the dying.
Fleet just does the flying.
Hold on. Something's up.
Fleet's mobilized for a big operation.
Attention on deck!
Once somebody asked me
if I knew the difference between
a citizen and a civilian.
I can tell you now.
A citizen has the courage
to make the safety of the human race
their personal responsibility.
Dizzy was my friend.
She was a soldier.
But more than that
she was a citizen of the Federation.
Present arms!
Order arms!
Left face!
-Officer on deck!
-Carry on.
Burial detail, dismissed.
At ease.
-How are you, Carl?
-Carmen, good.
Johnny, I'm sorry
it had to be your unit on P.
That mission had a very low
survival probability.
The bugs laid a trap for us, didn't they?
Elegant proof of intelligence, isn't it?
We thought there might be
a Brain Bug on P.
You knew, and you sent them anyway?
We couldn't afford to launch
an operation if there wasn't one.
You don't approve. Well, too bad.
We're in this for the species,
boys and girls.
It's simple numbers. They have more.
And every day I have
to make decisions
that send hundreds of people like you
to their deaths.
Didn't they tell you, Colonel?
That's what the Mobile Infantry
is good for.
I hope you're ready for more.
We're going back to P
to capture that Brain.
The Roughnecks are always ready, sir.
I hear they need a new lieutenant.
Want the job?
I'll take it, till I get killed
or you find someone better.
WOMAN ON PA: Attention.
All personnel report to your stations.
-Well...
-Prepare for drop in 75 minutes.
Take care of yourself, Johnny.
I'll see you again.
Officer on deck!
-Who are all these kids?
-We got reinforced.
Most of them are fresh out of boot.
We're the old men, Ace.
This is for all you new people.
I only have one rule,
everyone fights, no one quits.
If you don't do your job,
I'll kill you myself.
Do you get me?
We get you, sir!
-Welcome to the Roughnecks.
-Rico's Roughnecks!
(ALL GRUNT)
Today we're gonna pay a visit
to Bug City.
We're looking for a bug
no one's ever seen before.
Some kind of smart bug.
And it probably knows we're coming.
-Saddle up!
-TROOPER: Saddle up now!
Come on! Run! Run! Run! Run! Run!
Evasive action.
Get us clear for warp, Number Two.
Clear in five, four...
Initiating star drive in five.
(SHOUTING)
This is Rodger Young.
We're going down. Repeat, this is...
Get out! Abandon ship! Come on!
ZANDER: Carmen!
(ZANDER SHOUTING)
-Zander!
-Here!
-We've got to get to the rescue deck!
-Come on!
(SHOUTING)
Captain!
Abandon ship. That's an...
She's dead, Carmen. She's dead!
(PEOPLE SHOUTING)
ZANDER: Here!
Follow me!
CARMEN: Ready?
ZANDER: Hit it!
(ENGINE ROARING)
Life pod Bravo 6-3, two aboard.
Scanning for a landing zone!
Checking terrain. Here!
-Can you handle that?
-Piece of cake.
MAN ON RADIO:
We've lost the Rodger Young!
Flight Command,
we have confirmation.
The Rodger Young is down.
Johnny!
Rodger Young just burned up.
It's on the rescue net.
Any survivors?
Well, they're getting tarred
up there pretty bad.
...Bravo 6-3, two aboard.
Is anyone receiving?
Affirmative. This is Roughneck 2-0.
You're breaking up. Say again.
-Carmen'? Carmen!
-Say again. I'm losing you.
Prepare for landing.
Retros in three, two, one, fire!
Carmen. Carmen.
Hey, are you okay?
Get out. Get out. Get out.
RICO: This is Roughneck 2-0.
Are you receiving? Over.
This is Roughneck 2-0.
Carmen, are you receiving?
-Johnny, is that you?
-Yeah, it's me.
-What's your position and situation?
-Yeah.
We're in Bug City,
20 meters underground.
Position, south 42, east 118.
Situation is...
I repeat. South 42, east 118.
What's your situation? Over.
(GROWLING)
Carmen.
(ROARING)
The situation is extremely hostile.
(BUG SCREECHING)
I need a squad to pull 'em out!
-Direction?
-Three clicks, south by southwest.
Look out!
(BUG GROWLING)
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMS)
(STATIC ON RADIO)
-What do you wanna do?
-You heard the lieutenant.
Rescue party!
Third squad, come with me!
Cancel that!
You know as well as I do,
she's already dead.
Sorry, buddy.
Roughnecks, let's move.
All right.
(BUGS SHRIEKING)
(SHOUTS)
Why didn't they kill us?
They want us alive.
(CHITTERING)
(DEVICE BEEPING)
We should go this way.
A Company's that way.
Yeah, but Carmen's down there.
Hey, I hate to be rude, buddy,
but word has it she's dead.
She's still alive.
How do you know?
-I don't know how I know, but I know.
-Listen. You got command,
but going off mission...
-That's a serious offense.
-Yeah.
I think they hang you for that.
Roughneck 2-0, proceed on mission.
I need two volunteers.
(ACE SIGHING)
(BUGS SHRIEKING)
(GROWLING)
(GURGLING)
One day,
someone like me is gonna kill you
and your whole fucking race.
(SHOUTING)
(SLURPING)
(SHUDDERING)
(GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROWLS)
(ROARING)
(BUG SCREECHING)
(DEVICE BEEPING)
RICO: You know what this is?
(MIMICS EXPLOSION)
Sure you do.
You're some kind of big, fat,
smart bug, aren't you?
Come on.
(SHRIEKING AND GROWLING)
This is Roughneck 2-0.
Brain Bug sighted moving west
of grid five.
(BUG SNARLS)
Run!
Go! Go!
-Give me the nuke!
-You trying to be a hero, Watkins?
I'm trying to kill some bugs, sir!
Get outta here! Get outta here!
Move!
Come on! You like that?
You like that? Come on!
You want a little more?
You like that? You like that?
You like that? You want a little more?
Come on! Come on!
(ALL PANTING)
Come on, come on, come on!
RICO: Come on, Carmen.
(TROOPERS CHEERING)
TROOPER 1: We did it!
TROOPER 2: We won!
TROOPER 3: What's going on?
(ALL CHEERING)
-What's going on?
-We got it!
Come on.
Pull! Pull! Pull!
TROOPER: Quiet!
(BUG BREATHING HEAVILY)
What's it thinking, Colonel?
It's afraid.
It's afraid!
-Yeah!
(BUG ROARING)
CARMEN: Come on!
Yeah!
Carl! Carl! Hey!
Well, look who's here.
You made it. Good.
It was you, wasn't it?
You told me how to find Carmen.
Well, that's classified.
You know, whenever the three
of us are together,
I feel like things might just work out.
I hope you're right, Carmen.
We've got one of their brains now.
Pretty soon we'll know how they think.
And then we'll know how to beat them.
One day it will all be over
and everyone will forget
that this was the moment,
this is when it turned.
And it wasn't the mighty Fleet,
it wasn't some fancy new weapon.
It was a drill instructor named Zim
who captured a Brain.
Come on! Who am I?
-Yeah!
-Zim?
He got him! Yeah!
Zim. Zim got the bug.
Zim got the bug, man!
-Good job, Sergeant.
-Thank you, sir.
That would be private, sir.
-Carry on, Private.
-Yes, sir!
-Yeah!
(ALL CHEERING)
MAN ON TV: What mysteries will
the Brain Bug reveal?
Federal scientists are working
around the clock to probe its secrets.
Once we understand the bug,
we will defeat it.
We have the ships.
We have the weapons.
We need soldiers.
Soldiers like
Lieutenant Stack Lumbreiser.
We're over the target area now,
Captain.
-And Captain Carmen Ibanez.
-This is the captain speaking.
All personnel prepare for drop.
MAN ON TV: Soldiers like Private
Ace Levy and Lieutenant John Rico.
Come on, you apes!
You wanna live forever?
We need you all.
Service guarantees citizenship.